# Federico Ruttkay

Below is my Cover Letter and Curriculum Vitae, first in English, followed by Spanish.

A continuación se presenta mi Carta de Presentación y Currículum Vitae, tanto en inglés primero, como en español a continuación.

To Whom It May Concern,

I am writing to you to supplement the information presented in my CV, which is attached to this letter, given that my university education was in a different area from my current professional interests.

My tertiary education was in civil engineering at the Faculty of Engineering of UDELAR, and although it is a bachelor's degree (5-year duration), it has little connection with computer sciences. With the title of Civil Engineer, I developed professional tasks in various areas related to that career, but my interest in computer science was always present. Therefore, at the beginning of 2022, after several conversations with colleagues working in the field, I decided to finally start specific training in web development, initially opting to study HTML and CSS in-depth, then JavaScript, and finally React.

My goal from the beginning was to obtain solid training, not skipping intermediate steps merely to get a job, but understanding problems and solutions in an orderly and effective manner to become the best developer possible.

At this point, having completed various courses on the topics mentioned above, I wish to start developing myself in the field. My experience so far is through different types of exercises (some of which are showcased on my personal website, detailed in the CV), which over the months have led me to currently feel prepared to enter the job market.

As for myself, I am an organized person, who works very well in groups, and learns very quickly (which is why I initially decided to study all the subjects self-taught).

Although I have extensive work experience in positions that require a great capacity for analysis and problem-solving, I understand that hiring someone newly trained in a new discipline is an uncertainty for any employer. Therefore, I appreciate any opportunity you can provide, having no problem working on a trial basis for the time you consider appropriate to evaluate my work capacity.

Sincerely,

Federico Ruttkay

# Federico Ruttkay

+598 99 523 003 - fede.ruttkay@gmail.com

### PERSONAL INFORMATION:

### Date of Birth:

January 19, 1985

### ID:

3.864.186-2

### Personal Website (please visit it for examples of websites developed by me):

https://federico-ruttkay.netlify.app/

### LinkedIn Profile:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/federico-ruttkay/

### Driver's License:

Yes, type A.

### **Education:**

- Graduated as a Civil Engineer in 2013. Facultad de Ingeniería, Universidad de la República, Uruguay.
- Various studies in AutoCAD.
- Various studies in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React.

### Languages:

- Native Spanish.
- Fluent English with a First Certificate diploma. It's worth noting that both positions (detailed below) held at Dredging International NV required communication, both verbal and written, exclusively in English.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

# April 2021 - Present FAKTOR URUGUAY, Site Engineer.

Supervision of the construction of the "Derivador Averías" and its adjoining channels, which comprise the "Derivación y Conducción del Arroyo Averías" work, part of the "Plan de Regulación Hídrica de los Bañados de Rocha":

- On-site supervision of planned tasks execution, both in civil construction and earthworks.
- Data analysis.
- Remote report preparation.

# May 2016 - March 2021

### DINAMA - OSE.

Handling various procedures with organizations such as OSE or the National Directorate of Environment:

- Projects for the supply of new drinking water and/or sanitation networks.
- Execution control of said drinking water and sanitation networks.
- Project communications to DINAMA for various types of works.

### April 2014 - August 2017

### COLONIA DEPARTMENT GOVERNMENT, Site Engineer.

Responsible for municipal works carried out in different cities of the department, such as Carmelo, Nueva Palmira, Rosario, Tarariras, and Juan Lacaze, including:

- Coordination and supervision of personnel on-site.
- Quality control of executed works.
- Evaluation of future works to be carried out.

### March 2012 - January 2013

### DREDGING INTERNATIONAL NV, Project Engineer.

In charge of dredging works at the new Dock C of the Port of Montevideo, leading the work teams responsible for such tasks, including:

- Directing, organizing, and controlling personnel on-site, also serving as a liaison between vessels and the office.
- Work progress control.
- Organization of material and supply purchases.
- Handling documents and logistics for imports and exports.
- Negotiation with crew guilds regarding various requests.

# August 2011 - February 2012

### DREDGING INTERNATIONAL NV, Financial Assistant.

Assisting the Finance Department in various tasks during the dredging works at the Port of Conchillas, including:

- Invoicing and payment processing.
- Logistics for travel, accommodation, and medical insurance for crew members and foreign executives.
- Banking procedures.

### February 2009 - December 2009

### MONTEVIDEO DEPARTMENT GOVERNMENT - SOIL LABORATORY, Laboratory Technician.

Performing and analyzing various tests, including:

- Asphalt mixture strength (Marshall).
- Maximum theoretical density of asphalt mixture (Rice).
- Asphalt extraction.
- Concrete compression.
- Particle size distribution analysis.
- Field dry density of soils.
- Modified Proctor.
- CBR.

### ADDITIONAL PERSONAL INFORMATION:

## **Personal Attributes:**

- Excellent learning, communication, and organizational skills.
- Strong team player.
- Highly responsible.

## Personal and Professional References:

- Ing. Eduardo Ferreiro (Faktor Uruguay). Phone: +589 91 089 190.
- Federico Melo (web developer). Phone: +589 92 201 121.
- Esc. Eduardo Chocho. Phone: +589 94 407 880.
- Esc. Alicia Terilli. Phone: +589 99 520 822.

### A quién corresponda,

Por la presente me dirijo a Uds. para complementar la información expuesta en mi CV - adjunto a esta carta - dado que mi formación universitaria fue en un área diferente a la de mis actuales intereses profesionales.

Mi formación terciaria fue en ingeniería civil en la Facultad de Ingeniería de la UDELAR, y si bien es un título de grado (duración 5 años) tiene una baja vinculación con las ciencias informáticas. Con el título de Ingeniero Civil desarrollé tareas profesionales en diversas áreas afines a dicha carrera, pero mi interés en la informática siempre estuvo presente, por lo que a principios de 2022, luego de conversaciones varias con colegas que trabajan en el área me decido a finalmente iniciar una formación específica en desarrollo web, optando inicialmente por estudiar en profundidad HTML y CSS, luego JavaScript, y finalmente React.

Mi objetivo desde el comienzo fue obtener una sólida formación, no salteando pasos intermedios con el mero objetivo de conseguir un trabajo, sino entendiendo los problemas y las soluciones de manera ordenada y efectiva para convertirme en el mejor desarrollador posible.

En este punto me encuentro ahora, habiendo finalizado diversos cursos de las temáticas expresadas anteriormente, y con el deseo de comenzar a desarrollarme en el área. Mi experiencia de momento es a través de ejercicios de distinto tipo (algunos de ellos se exponen en mi web personal, la cual se detalla en el CV), los cuales con el paso de los meses me han llevado a actualmente sentirme preparado para ingresar al mercado laboral.

En cuanto a mi, soy una persona ordenada, que se desarrolla muy bien trabajando en grupos, y que aprende muy rápido (por eso fue que desde un principio decidí estudiar todas las temáticas de manera autodidacta).

Si bien cuento con vasta experiencia laboral en puestos que requieren que gran capacidad de análisis y resolución de problemas, entiendo que contratar a alguien recién formado en una nueva disciplina es una incertidumbre para todo empleador. Es por ello que agradezco cualquier oportunidad que me puedan brindar, no teniendo problema en trabajar a prueba durante el tiempo que consideren oportuno para evaluar mi capacidad de trabajo.

Sin más, saluda muy atte.,

Federico Ruttkay.

# Federico Ruttkay

+598 99 523 003 - fede.ruttkay@gmail.com

### **DATOS PERSONALES:**

### Fecha de Nacimiento

19 de enero de 1985

### Cédula de Identidad

3.864.186-2

Web Personal (por favor ingresar allí para ver ejemplos de webs desarrolladas por mi) https://federico-ruttkay.netlify.app/

### Perfil de LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/federico-ruttkay/

### Carné de conducir

Si, libreta tipo A.

#### Formación

- Graduado como Ingeniero Civil, perfil construcción, en 2013. Facultad de Ingeniería, Universidad de la República, Uruguay.
- Estudios varios de AutoCAD.
- Estudios varios de HTML, CSS, JavaScript y React.

### **Idiomas**

- Castellano nativo.
- Inglés fluido con diploma First Certificate. Cabe destacar que ambos puestos (detallados más adelante) ocupados en Dredging International NV requerían comunicación tanto verbal como escrita exclusivamente en inglés.

### **EXPERIENCIA LABORAL:**

### Abril 2021 - Presente

### FAKTOR URUGUAY, Ing. Supervisor de Obras.

Supervisión de la construcción del Derivador Averías y sus canales anexos, los cuales componen la obra de Derivación y Conducción del Arroyo Averías, integrante del Plan de Regulación Hídrica de los Bañados de Rocha:

- Supervisión a pie de obra de la ejecución de las tareas proyectadas, tanto de construcción de la obra civil como de movimientos de suelos.
- Análisis de datos.
- Elaboración de informes de manera remota.

### Mayo 2016 - Marzo 2021 DINAMA - OSE.

Realización de trámites varios frente a organismos como ser OSE o la Dirección Nacional de Medio Ambiente:

- Proyectos de abastecimiento de nuevas redes de agua potable y/o saneamiento.
- Control de ejecución de dichas redes de agua potable y saneamiento.
- Comunicaciones de proyecto frente a DINAMA para obras de variada índole.

### Abril 2014 - Agosto 2017

### INTENDENCIA DE COLONIA, Director de Obras.

Responsable de las obras municipales realizadas en distintas ciudades del departamento, como ser Carmelo, Nueva Palmira, Rosario, Tarariras y Juan Lacaze, incluyendo:

- Coordinación y dirección del personal en obra.
- Control de calidad de las obras ejecutadas.
- Evaluación de obras futuras a ser realizadas.

### Marzo 2012 - Enero 2013

### DREDGING INTERNATIONAL NV, Ingeniero de Proyecto.

A cargo de las obras de dragado del nuevo Muelle C del puerto de Montevideo, liderando los equipos de trabajo responsables de dichas tareas, incluyendo:

- Dirección, organización y control de personal en obra, funcionando a su vez como nexo entre las embarcaciones y la oficina de obra.
- Control de avance de obra.
- Organización de compras de materiales e insumos.
- Manejo de documentos y logística de importaciones y exportaciones.
- Negociación con gremios de tripulantes ante solicitudes de variada índole.

### Agosto 2011 - Febrero 2012

# DREDGING INTERNATIONAL NV, Asistente Financiero.

Asistiendo al Departamento Financiero en diversas tareas durante la ejecución de los trabajos de dragado del Puerto de Conchillas, incluyendo:

- Procesamiento de facturación y pagos.
- Logística de viajes, hospedaje y seguro médico para tripulantes y directivos extranjeros.
- Trámites bancarios.

### Febrero 2009 - Diciembre 2009

### INTENDENCIA DE MONTEVIDEO - LABORATORIO DE SUELOS, Técnico de Laboratorio.

Realizando y analizando ensayos varios, incluyendo:

- Resistencia de mezcla asfáltica (Marshall).
- Densidad máxima teórica de mezcla asfáltica (Rice).
- Extracción de asfalto.
- Compresión del hormigón.
- Estudio granulométrico.
- Densidad seca en sitio de suelos.
- Proctor Modificado.
- CBR.

### DATOS PERSONALES COMPLEMENTARIOS:

## **Atributos Personales**

- Muy buena capacidad de aprendizaje, de comunicación y de organización.
- Muy bueno trabajando en equipos.
- Muy responsable.

# Referencias Personales y Laborales

- Ing. Eduardo Ferreiro (Faktor Uruguay). Cel.: 091 089 190.
- Federico Melo (desarrollador web). Cel.: 092 201 121.
- Esc. Eduardo Chocho. Cel.: 094 407 880.
- Esc. Alicia Terilli. Cel.: 099 520 822.